

OLAKUNLE IBRAHIM

SOFTWARE | DATA ENGINEER ♥ SWEDEN • 0736565835

• DETAILS •

Sweden 0736565835 klexy2402@gmail.com

> Driving license B

> > LINKS

WEB-Portfolio

o SKILLS o

Communication Skills

Good team player

Flexibility and Adaptability

Data Engineering (BigQuery, Tensorflow)

Data Analysis (Power BI, Qlik, Excel))

Machine Learning (Data Modelling and Training - KNIME)

Programming Language (Java, C#, JavaScript, Python)

Development Framework (React.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Spring Boot & JPA, Selenium, Jenkins, TeamCity, Ghostlab, Android Studio)

Database (MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB)

Cloud Computing (Google Cloud, MS Azure, AWS)

UI/UX

Digital Marketing

HOBBIES

Travelling, Football, Chess game, Gym

PROFILE

Experienced in design, building, Implementation, testing, integration, delivery, QA, and maintenance of software systems. Proficient in different development platforms, programming languages, data engineering and analytic, machine learning, artificial and business intelligence, and information system management. Experienced with the latest development tools, technologies, and procedures. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Engineer at Cabonline Group, Stockholm

November 2021 — Present

- Develop algorithms and perform data exploration to transform data to information and knowledge.
- Acquire quality datasets to build data model for business needs.
- Design, build, and test data pipeline and database architecture.
- Create new data validation and data analysis.
- Ensure compliance with governance and security policies of data. Collaboration with management in achieving company objectives.
- · Agile methodology

Software / Data Specialist at TISV Digital, Atlanta, Georgia. & Lagos, Nigeria

December 2018 — Present

- 1. Quality Assurance Analyst (June, 2019 Dec., 2019)
- 2. System Tester (Dec., 2018 June, 2019)
- Developing and architecture training on software systems, systems test to identify failure points and ensure quality software for release to production.
- Application back-end (Java, JavaScript)
- Performing continuous integration and delivery of product quality.
- · Working with clients to gather requirements. Agile methodology

IT Specialist/ Cashier/ Assistant at Hubertus Restaurant, Stockholm

August 2015 — December 2016

- Booking and mailing management. System and database administration.
- Worked productively with Restaurant Team to provide better customer service experience and ensure customer satisfaction at all time.

Computer Specialist at Softline Communication Company, Ado Odo

June 2006 — June 2012

- Worked on data input, data management, and electronic data transfer.
- System back-end (C#, Java).
- · Bulk messaging and emailing.
- Ensuring database security and integrity.
- Develop IT equipment, process related documents and system applications

Information Officer (Consultant) at House of Representative Office, Lagos/Abuja

June 2009 — May 2012

LANGUAGES

English

Swedish

System development.

- Database design and management.
- ICT strategy and implementation, Special duties and social engagement.

Production Manager at Narconon Nigeria (NGO), Lagos

June 2007 — May 2012

- Developed strategies for events and productivity and project lead.
- Coordinate partnership and corroborate UNODC concepts.

System Administrator at Expert Services, Lagos

June 2004 — June 2006

- Install, upgrade and monitor software, hardware and networks.
- Monitoring system performance and troubleshooting issues.

Hardware Software Technician at YNS Technology, Lagos

June 2003 — June 2004

- Support and maintain in-house technology equipment and IT systems.
- Configuring and repairing hardware and software application for optimal performance.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information System, Lund University, Lund

August 2020 — June 2021

Bachelor of Science in Software Development, Kristianstad University, Kristianstad

August 2017 — June 2020

Diploma in Computer Science, Kwara State Polytechnic, Ilorin

September 2001 — December 2003

CERTIFICATION

Secure Software Development Fundamentals, LinuxFoundationX

February 2022

Unlocking Information Security, TelAvivUniversity, IsraelX

December 2021

Data Engineering with Google Cloud

November 2021

Digital Marketing Certificate, Google Fundamental Digital Marketing

April 2019

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Assistant Field Communicator/ Reporter at BBC, Lagos

2009 - 2010

Radio 5 UK.

Documentary about Nigeria Cultures and Traditions

Lead Field Communicator at UK DragonFly TV, Lagos

2010 - 2010

Project: Lagos Documentary

REFERENCES

References available upon request